

#### COMPUTER SCIENCE ENGINEERING STUDENT

Manzano 551, Recoleta, Santiago, Chile

□ (+569) 90949338 | Soaestay@uc.cl | Ahttps://oaestay.github.io/ | Doaestay | Doaestay

# Summary\_

Current Software Engineer in Notus, a company that develops and implements solutions based in optimization and simulation for business management. My main tasks are the development of web applications, optimization models and simulation models. My specialty is algorithm design and implementation, and backend development; but I certainly love to learn and work the latest technologies not only in backend, but also in frontend and mobile. I also have experience with a variety of frameworks (mostly web frameworks), databases and tools, such as Vue, NodeJS, Django, Ruby on Rails, LAMP, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, Docker, Amazon AWS.

I'm interested in developing solutions for concrete problems, of diverse complexity, using modern technologies and best coding practices so that they remain being used for a long period of time.

# Work Experience

**Notus** Santiago, Chile

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Oct. 2016 - Present

- Development of web application that generates optimization models taking an Excel-like input in the browser
- Implementation and application of data mining algorithms
- Development of different optimization models
- Development of a simulation model for an assignment problem

**Artorta** Santiago, Chile

 Web Developer
 2015 - 2016

- Development of web application, using LAMP, to showcase and manage a cake shop's products
- Development of web application, using Ruby on Rails, to showcase and manage a cake shop's products

## Honors & Awards \_

3rd place, Facebook's 2017 Hackathon
 Recognition for results obtained in PSU (University Selection Test), Sociedad de Instrucción Primaria
 Santiago, Chile

2012 **Recognition for results obtained in PSU (University Selection Test)**, Sociedad de Instrucción Primaria *Santiago, Chile* 2000 - 2012 **Appreciation for performance in middleschool and highschool**, Rafael Sanhueza Lizardi *Santiago, Chile* 

#### **Education**

### Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile

Santiago, Chile

COMPUTER SCIENCE ENGINEERING

Mar. 2013 - Exp. Aug. 2018

Skills

Advanced Knowledge Python, Javascript, Django, Express, Git

Intermediate Knowledge C, C#, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, React, SQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL

MongoDB, Redis, Docker, CSS

**Basic Knowledge** Java, Nginx, Webpack, SASS, LAMP

**Deployment Experience** Amazon AWS, Digital Ocean, Heroku, Django, Express, Ruby on Rails

**Experience with Agile Development Methodologies** Kanban, Scrum

Experience with different system arquitectures

**Experience working with teams of diverse sizes** 

**Advanced Photoshop skills** 

Strong spirit of teamwork and responsibility

**Languages** English, Spanish (Mothertongue)